Hello, the Fundamentals training set in
plain language has been made available to the Frachart site for public and free use.
I hope you will pay attention to it. Hello
and greetings to you, dear friends. Good time,
I hope you are well. I am Alireza Madadhi. I
am at your service with the fifth part of the Fundamentals training set in plain language.
Guys, in the previous parts, we
talked about economic cycles based on inflation and growth. We
talked about how important these are and why
we use them. In this part, we
want to go to the topic of sentiment, which you have definitely
heard of. It is an analytical style.
They call it sentimental. It is something like this, the name of which is
not very important now. Let's learn sentiment or market sentiment
together. Let's see what it is. I will
explain it to you simply, like in the
previous videos. So that you can easily remember these
things in your mind.
I will tell you one thing right here. Guys, this
series that I am creating has a series of headings
that I have already prepared. I know
what I am going to tell you by the fifteenth or sixteenth part, but
I will probably continue the series in a few more parts,
and in the last parts,
I will explain the details related to the fundamentals, and
those
details, well, there are points in it that are useful for the trader. You could
say that they are empirical things that I have
gained in the years that I have been involved in the market. One thing that
could be very good for you is to
come and ask your questions, tell me what
problems you have that need more explanation, so that
I can dedicate more time
to these issues and topics in the last videos. That is,
you come now and tell me what
problems you have, what is needed, and I will
explain more, I will spend more time on it.
We will create and present those last videos based on your needs. So be
sure to
subscribe to Instagram, where you can
ask me your questions, and
if necessary, I will definitely provide you with further explanations in the form of a
video at the end of the series.
This was the point I wanted to tell you,
but let's move on to the
fifth part, the topic of sentiment. We want to
learn a little more about financial assets, and from here on, the
story will probably become a little more interesting for you.  Because
we go into the heart of the market, we examine the fluctuations, events, and
changes that we had
and talk about them. The topic of sentiment
can be said to be newer than the technical or
fundamental topic, or maybe it has
not been addressed as it should be. It is something that
has more to do with market emotions, that is, how the market feels.
We call it sentiment. What is the basis of the market? Is
the market scared? Is it greedy? Is it happy? Is it
satisfied with the economic conditions? Or does it
see a risk? This is called sentiment. In
general, if I were to define sentiment,
sentiment means the
mood of the market. The market is also composed of traders.
What is the mood of traders? Let
me give you an example. For example, one
of the things that we use a lot, a
platform that we use a lot,
is Twitter. There are all kinds of
analysts and institutions on Twitter, and I don't know, banks, and all of
them are present and they tweet about the market on a
daily basis.
We have an indicator called
Twitter sentiment. What does Twitter sentiment do?
Twitter sentiment comes and says that the set  Tweets
that were made today about the financial markets,
were the tweets positive or negative?
Was the trader's perspective positive or negative?
If it was positive, then the sentiment is
good. The market mood is growing. The conditions are good. Everyone is
happy. If it was negative, then it
is clearly bad for the market. This
market mood is called sentiment and it is very influential in market fluctuations.
Guys, I will tell you something
here. In the fundamentals topic, we are
not going to get to a single factor and
say that with this factor, you
can examine the financial markets and get the fluctuations,
how they were and why they moved. It is
not one thing that moves the market. We
have several factors in the fundamentals topic that are important together and must
be examined one by one. That is, in
fundamentals, for example, the monetary policies of the
central bank are important to us. Economic growth of the country is
important to us. Geopolitical conditions are important to us.
How do trading partners work? These are
important to us. These are all part of the
fundamentals now.  The most important thing for the
forex market, for example, is the monetary policies of the
central bank and the interest rate, which we will now discuss in a
separate video, but I want to say that there is
no one thing that moves the market. There are a number of
factors and factors that go together
and form the fluctuations of the financial markets.
So let's explain together the types of
financial assets based on risk. I'll
leave this here and use my pen. I had
n't prepared my pen and I have to go and
activate my pen for a moment. I apologize to you. So
let's start with the pen. So then,
we guys have the topic of sentiment and first of
all, we went to the types of financial assets
based on risk. Guys, we have two categories of assets:
one is risky assets and two is
assets. You hear this a lot in the market.
They say that risky assets are growing, they are growing.
On the contrary, they
say that safe assets have increased demand for them, they are
growing, or savings bonds have grown.
So in the market, you can say that we have two categories of
assets: one is  Risky assets and two
safe assets, assets that
have low risk. Now between these, we have a series of
assets that can be said to have both properties.
Now, depending on the circumstances,
how they act is different. It
depends on the circumstances. Now,
what are the characteristics of risky assets? They have higher risk. That is,
for our investment, if we want to
choose them, we have taken a higher risk,
but they also bring us a higher profit. That
is, the higher the risk, the higher the profit.
For example, with an investment of 20, you are taking a risk of
30. You are likely to make a
gain. The higher the risk, the
higher the probability of your reward.
Riskier means that an asset that has a 50% probability of
default, for example, is likely to
default or disappear.
For example, you buy shares of a company and the company goes
bankrupt. This asset has a higher risk
than an asset that has a 20% probability of bankruptcy.
That is, these risks also
have different classes. Now, we are
talking in general here about what
characteristics do risky assets have? What characteristics do safe assets have?
China's safe assets  Safe assets or
safe havens, learn these two in English
because they are important and you will
come across them in the market in your activity in the financial markets.
Well, you
didn't. So, safe assets, we said what their
characteristics are. Lower risk, lower risk and
lower profit. That means you are making an investment
with lower risk, but the profit you
earn
is definitely lower than risky assets. So that's it. We
have two asset classes that we need to know.
Now let's move on to parallel markets. Guys,
we deal with parallel markets a lot.
In the topic of inter-market analysis, in the topic of
central bank monetary policies, we deal with these four
markets a lot. And
I'll tell you one thing right here. Guys, the
transactional trader that I saw working in banks is
not really a trader, let's say, for example, he
focuses on the euro-dollar situation and,
for example, he only trades this. I
really haven't seen anything like that until now. That's all.  I
followed the banks, I
tried to follow successful traders, but I did
not see such a case where, for example, the other party says, "
I am only trading gold.
Now, maybe, for example, in gold, because he has
spent a lot of time on it empirically and
gained more experience. Maybe that trader is more skilled in gold.
But guys, a trader cannot
choose a market and say, "I will only
choose this market." Especially for us
in Iran, who trade international markets,
that is, our options are limited. For example,
you see a person in the US stock market. There
are thousands of shares there, and only the stock market
works. He does fundamental analysis of the stock market and
buys and sells them on the stock market. He is okay.
Well, no problem. However,
if this person follows parallel markets, he will get
much better results. He will get much
better results. So, guys, a trader
cannot say, "I will only trade one market,
commodity, for example, ounces, I
do not want to trade the rest. My focus is
only on the bond market. Sometimes, it is not  It
gives you signals that
you can make a profit in the stock market, for example, the
commodity market gives a signal that
you can make a profit in the forex market. So let's get to
know the parallel markets: one
bond market, two stock markets, the forex market,
and the commodity market or raw materials like oil and
gold, and I don't know about copper and coal, and so on. So we've got to know the
assets of the parallel markets here.
Now let's move on to
sentiment, or market sentiment, or investor sentiment, what is it?
Guys, we generally
have two types of sentiment. To
put it very simply, sentiment in which the
investor is afraid to take more risk,
afraid of taking risk, unwilling to
take more risk. That is, you see the mood of the
economy, the economic conditions in a way that
says, "I'm not taking any more risk in this
investment. The market is not a place for me to take
risks anymore." This sentiment is called
risk-averse sentiment, or risk-off sentiment, meaning turn
off the risk, turn it off. What is the opposite of
risk-taking sentiment, or risk-on sentiment, meaning
turn the risk on, turn it up? What happens in this scenario?
Investors are willing to take
more risk, meaning they are willing to take more risk
in order to make more profit.
Now, when does this
happen? You see, an economy that is growing is
moving up. Well, everything is good.
Companies are making profits. They are selling. People are
creating demand. Those previous videos that
we talked about economic growth. When
we have this kind of situation in the economy, the
investor says, "There is no room for fear now. There is no
reason to be afraid. So I can
take more risk and
invest in small assets that will
give me higher profits." But at some point, you see that the
conditions are not conditions. The conditions are difficult. The
investor sees that there are a number of
factors that can
create the risk that assets will decline, their
prices will decrease, interest rates
will decrease, and the market that we want to invest in will not be able to make the
profit we want. In
these conditions, we will be afraid of risking. In the
market, there is a sentiment called risk. So we have two types of
sentiments: risk, risk, risk-taking,
risk-aversion.  Risk-taking sentiment means that we
accept risk, we are willing to take more
risk, we are willing to take more risk
in order to get higher profits. But
in risk-averse sentiment, it is exactly the opposite, we are
not willing to take risks,
and this causes
us to move towards our assets. Now I
will explain further. Well, in risk-
taking sentiment, kids,
capital moves out
of safe assets,
safe assets move out towards
risky assets. In risk-
averse sentiment, capital moves out of risky assets and
towards safe assets. That is,
sentiment affects like this. A change in
sentiment causes the flow of money and liquidity to
shift between safe assets and safe assets. Risk-taking I
move towards riskier assets in order to
get more rewards or profits. In
risk-taking sentiment, I move towards
safe assets because the conditions are not good. I
want to make a safe investment. So
this is how the change in market fluctuations looks like, that
is, sentiment is affecting like this. Let's
go.  The next slide is going to
examine the effect of sentiment here and assets
based on those safe assets and
risky assets. Let's examine it. Guys,
look at sentiment like a pendulum. In the market, every day, for
example, a little bit of the risk-off sentiment
becomes risk or a little bit, for example,
this week is starting.
For example, we are moving from the risk-off side
to the risk-off side. This causes fluctuations
in assets due to sentiment. We
said, if the sentiment is risk-off and becomes
risk-off, that is, we move towards the risk-off side,
what happens? Capital moves out of safe assets and
goes towards my assets. So the
pendulum is constantly changing. Now, what
affects sentiment? What
causes market sentiment to change?
Economic data and news. Guys,
sentiment is generally fed by these two. It is
affected by these two. That is, the
economic data that we have throughout the day.
In the calendar, which I will explain in detail now,
we have a separate video, two or three videos about the calendar
and  We have data and this. The data that
we have in the financial markets, the economic calendar, for
example, Forex Factory. You all know
Forex Factory. When you open it, a lot of
data comes in during the week. One, they have an impact.
Two, there are some news that come out of the calendar. For
example, I do
n't know, North Korea is in conflict with Japan. I do
n't know, North Korea has launched a missile that
landed near Japanese soil. This can be
news in the market. Or, for example, the president of
Russia said something about oil.
This can be
news that comes out of the
calendar. Or, for example, the Suez Canal has run into trouble and is closed. This can be news that comes out of the calendar. Or, the US president said something like this. The
Japanese finance minister said something like this. The
US treasury secretary said something like this. These can be
news that comes out of the calendar. And these also
affect the market and cause sentiment to
change. Now, let's get to know the assets together, the
safe assets and the
risky assets. And see how
this classification of children's risk or risk sentiment, as I
told you, causes
Risk assets grow, or
are high yield or risky assets, meaning assets
that have higher returns, and
having higher returns means that they have
higher risk, so their risk sentiment or
risk-taking sentiment grows.
Now what are these assets? The
stock market, guys, we generally call
it a risky asset, meaning stocks are a
risky asset. Now there is one thing. In the
stock market itself, guys, we have different industries,
for example, there are a number of defensive industries,
meaning that when a problem
occurs and the risk sentiment is off, investors try to
take their capital there. Now I have not
included the types of industries in this category anymore. It is
not the subject of our discussion here, but you should know that
in the stock market, we have
different assets. We have risky assets, we
have safe assets. Depending on
the conditions, the flows in the stock market can change,
but in general, either the average
stock market is a high or a risky asset
is a risky asset.
In the risk sentiment, it grows.
In our second category,
we have commodities. Commodities
are also mostly risky assets, meaning they have
higher returns and higher risks.
And as the risk sentiment grows, they
also weaken in the risk-off sentiment. So
commodities are also risky assets.
But there are still exceptions.
For example, we cannot consider gold as a
completely risky asset. There is something neutral in the
middle of gold. And we come to the
forex market, where we have the IDRs and the CODs,
which we call
commodity currencies or risk currencies. These
guys are commodity-exporting countries,
and their risk sentiment grows. I
will explain more to you later. Now let's move on to the
risk-off category, where
we have safe assets here, we
have the securities here, or the risk-off, as we
said, risk-aversion. We have the
risk-off sentiment or the situation in which
investors feel afraid in the market.
We call this sentiment risk sentiment.
We say the mood, the mood of fear in the
financial markets. Now what assets
are there here? We have bonds as a
safe asset, the US dollar, which we know as the
Japanese yen, and the
Swiss franc. These assets
are safe assets. I will tell you why these are
safe and why they are risky. We also have a series of assets,
guys, in the middle, the euro, the pound, and gold, which
are now well-known and well-known assets. I couldn't put them in the table, but I
couldn't say whether they are risky or not.
These guys are
safe assets. In general, they can
go in any of these categories. They can go
in safe assets, they
can
go in risky assets, high-risk assets. Now I will give you more explanations. It fits
perfectly for you. Let's move on to the
next item, where we guys have the analysis of news
and economic data. I told you
what affects sentiment, news, and
Economic data, this news, we now
call it news outside the economic calendar.
News outside the economic calendar. Well, you have to, I want to
apologize. You
have to follow them on, for example, different sites or
Telegram channels. And I invite you to
your presence. There are a number of terminals. There are a number of sites.
For example, I
will introduce you to a site called Forex Live.
You can follow this site. It
also brings you news outside the calendar. It brings you news
that is related to and affects the Forex market.
Now, type Forex Live in Google
Maps. I think it boils down to the fact that
we should follow the news, except for the corporate calendar. This
news cannot be ignored. Although it is true that, for
example, if we want to give them weight, 90
sentiment events are the same data inside the calendar
and 10 are news events. Well, these are
not without influence. You can see somewhere that these
news are much more influential than
economic data. So, we want
you guys to learn how to analyze economic news and
data.
How does this affect sentiment?
We said that these have an impact. Now how do you
guys do? Every piece of news, every piece of data,
creates expectations of economic growth.
That is, data comes into the market, for example, a confidence
index, that is, consumer confidence.
They survey
consumers. They ask them, "Sir, how do you see the economic situation? How do you see the
various factors that exist?
How do they affect
your purchases? Maybe your feelings, etc." A
number is obtained, for example, 80 or 70. This
shows how confident the consumer is in the
economy. The higher this number is, the
higher our expectations of growth are. In the
market, there is an increase in expectations of growth.
Economic growth. I mean, when expectations of
economic growth increase, investors are
more willing to take risks. This is where
those cycles that we mentioned in previous meetings are
effective. We had a growth cycle and
a recession cycle. Guys, any news that causes
us to move the growth cycle towards a growth cycle
causes its risk sentiment to change, and any news that
causes us to move towards a cycle  Let's go to recession.
Sentiment can be risk-off. So news that
causes a decrease in economic growth or a recession
ultimately causes us to have risk-off.
And any news that causes expectations of growth to rise
causes the risk to arise here. So,
what kind of news do we analyze based on sentiment? We
filter the news based on economic growth. We say, will
this news increase expectations of
economic growth or decrease expectations of
economic growth? And this can change market sentiment.
If it increases, the risk appetite
will increase. The risk appetite will increase, meaning
that risk will arise and
we have the growth of risky assets. The capital, the kids, will go
to risky assets. It will come
out of safe assets and go here. And
vice versa. If there is news or data that
causes expectations of growth to decrease,
fear of risk arises. Sentiment becomes
risk-off and a decline in risky assets
occurs, meaning that capital will go from here and
enter safe assets. From risky assets
to safe assets.  This is the impact of
economic news and data on sentiment, guys.
We need to know what affects sentiment
and how. Knowing this, we can
learn the impact of economic news and data based on sentiment and profit from market fluctuations.
So let's move on to introducing
risky assets. Which risky assets
are they and why are they risky? Why are they risky? Guys, it's
important because sometimes we
have some exceptions in the market. Now, I'll give
you an example of what the
first and second things we had in risk sentiment
or risk sentiment were.
Where did a stock market go? The stock
market, well, the stock market, Bush. When we said that the stock
market or the stock market is a risky asset,
in general, we said that there are exceptions in the
stock market itself, which are two categories.
So, guys, let's move on to introducing
risky assets and yields. What are they like? I
want to have a definition of
risky assets. Guys, any asset whose increase in value
or price depends on economic growth,
we call it an asset.  Risk means that
economic growth is good for that asset
and the price or demand for it increases.
We came to say that the stock market is
a risky asset. It is a risky stock.
Why is the stock market risky now? Because
guys, the higher the economic growth, the
higher the income of companies. And the increase in the income of
companies causes the most profitable
and profitable ones to
increase their prices. So the price of stocks
depends on economic growth
and that is how the stock market is affected by this
issue. Now, if we
have a decrease in economic growth, it causes the income of that
company to decrease. The decrease in
profitability and the decrease in price means we have a negative impact
on the side of reducing economic growth. The second market
or that asset, our second risk,
is commodities, the commodity market or the
raw materials market, and so on. What is the issue here?
Why is it risky? Because the increase in
economic growth causes  There can be demand for
these materials, for these assets,
and they can have an increase in price growth.
For example, you consider the
US economy. Suppose the economic growth is good.
This will cause the
demand for, I don't know, the demand for steel, the
demand for oil, the demand for other raw materials to
increase. And consider a
scenario where the US economic situation is
not good. Well, of course, US demand or
US purchases will decrease in these assets, in these
raw materials, and this will cause their prices to decrease.
Because with the increase in demand, the price will go up.
So these depend on the growth rate. The
higher the economic growth, the
higher their prices. The lower the economic growth, the
lower the demand for them, and we have a decrease in value
for these assets. Now let's go to the
Canadian dollar. Let's examine
why it is a risky asset and why.
Guys,
we have a number of countries that can be said to be
dependent countries. In the world economy, a
number of countries are the main countries and we can say that they
are our core. For example, which countries are the US, China, and
Europe? We call these countries core countries,
meaning those that are driving the global economy. The core is the core.  The
global economy has a number of countries, we
call them dependent countries or here we
call them shell. One
could
say that I was reading an article
about a theory. Yes, there was another theory of core and
shell. It explained that some
countries are core and some are shell.
Now what happens? Shell countries
are dependent on core countries. For example,
look at Canada, an economy that accounts for 73% of
its exports,
or three-quarters of its exports, to the United
States. Look at how much the
US economy affects the Canadian economy.
Suppose the US economy weakens. It will
cause Americans to
have less demand for Canadian goods,
and the Canadian economy will also weaken.
We can see here that the dependence of the Canadian economy on the US economy is
73% of its exports to the
US. Then it becomes China, two and a half percent,
Japan, and two and a half percent, the United Kingdom.
Look at our trading partners.
We need to
know them so that we can understand
the influence and impact of economies on
each other. That's why,
kids, we say the US
dollar or the US dollar.  X-Wa
has a correlation with the code. That's why
their correlation is that the Canadian economy
is dependent on the US economy. I gave
you an example. If the US economy is doing well,
the demand for Canadian goods will increase, and
this will cause Canadian exports to increase to the US.
And the increase in Canadian exports to the
US will cause us to have more economic growth
in Canada.
Now, what does Canada export? It
can be said
that a
large part of its exports goes back to
commodities. That is, this part, the commodity part, of which
nearly 17% is petroleum or
US petroleum products. Guys, Canada
imports fuel from Canada. Canada is one of the
largest producers of oil and gas
in the world. Of course, the US itself is the largest,
but it has such a high need or demand
for commodities that it also imports oil from Canada. So
guys,
that strategic commodity of Canada is crude
petroleum or oil, and its trading partner is the
US. Look at how much more America's influence
on Canada is than China's. If something happens to the Chinese economy, it doesn't matter much to Canadians,
but on the other hand, if something happens to the US, it won't matter much to Canadians.  If
something happens to America,
Canada will definitely be affected. Its economy will be affected.
So, guys, we have realized two things here.
First, the Canadian dollar
is correlated with oil. Second, the
Canadian economy is working with the US economy
and they are trading partners with each other. The
Canadian economy is affected by the
US economy. Now, if we reverse it, that is, we
want to see what American exports are like.
The situation is different. It is
not the Canadian economy that is the first
customer of American goods. For example,
China and Europe are the largest trading partners of America.
But for Canada itself,
this percentage, like this, seventeen percent
of exports are only to the US. This is what causes
this correlation. We
need to know the reasons for the correlation. Now,
how does this correlation exist in the market?
Here we see the price of oil
and the USD code. I brought you a picture of it, so let's not
just talk about it and give you an example so that you can understand it.
Here, guys, we have the price of oil. The
red chart and  The price of the USD
code, which is the code in the denominator of our fraction, and we
have to look at this graph in reverse, that is, if you
reverse one of the graphs, you will notice that there is a
direct correlation between the Canadian dollar and oil.
Now how does this happen?
This correlation, this relationship, this correlation,
guys, remember that if the price of oil
goes up, for example, let's consider the price of oil at $50.
In a scenario, if the price of oil
is $100, if the price of oil is $50, Americans
must
convert their dollars to Canadian dollars in order to import oil from Canada. And if it
is $550, fewer dollars. If the price of oil
is $50, they must convert their money to
Canadian dollars to import that oil.
But
if
the price of oil increases, they must
pay a higher price for that oil to
Canada, and this causes the demand for the
Canadian dollar to be higher and the price of the Canadian dollar to
grow. So we have a
direct correlation between the Canadian dollar and oil,
meaning that if the price of oil goes up, the Canadian dollar will
also grow. Now it's the
other way around. The price of oil, for example, has gone
down here, and the USD code has gone up, which means the price of
oil has decreased.  Here the
Canadian dollar has also weakened, as the dollar has gained
strength against the Canadian dollar. So the first correlation is
this. The second correlation we said is that the Canadian economy and the
US economy are related to each other.
Now here you see the correlation between two currency pairs.
What is it like here? I will
record the video. Yes, here we have correlation. I would like to
invite
you to see two currency pairs.
Now let's go and see. I don't remember myself. The
Euro-US Dollar and the Euro Code mean that the Euro is on one side. I
put the Canadian Dollar and the US Dollar
against the Euro. The correlation is quite clear. The
US and Canadian economies are
moving together. And the Code
has a correlation with the Euro-USD Code. Or, for example, the Pound-
USD Code has a correlation with the Pound-USD Code. Because the
Canadian dollar and the US dollar, the
US economy, the Canadian economy are
moving in the same direction. They are correlated.
If the dollar strengthens, it will make the Canadian dollar
stronger. If the dollar weakens, it will make the
Canadian dollar weaker. Now, it's not that
they always move together. There is a divergence,
meaning there is a small fundamental difference
between them that causes  Can the
US dollar fluctuate? If these two were
moving together, and the price
was always constant, it would not cause the US dollar to
move. There is a small divergence. Now that
divergence could be a divergence between
monetary policies. It could be a divergence. The
oil price could cause, for example, one dollar to be stronger and one dollar to be
weaker. Or some other reason.
So the second collision is between the dollar itself and the dollar, or
between the US and Canadian economies. Let's go to the
Australian dollar. We are talking about those risky assets
that we said the NZD
dollar has risk. What is the story of the Australian dollar? Australia
is a country that is now dependent on
China. What percentage of its exports are dependent on
China? Then Japan, then South Korea, then
India, then Chinese
Taipei, and Singapore, and other Asian countries. Then it
goes to Europe and
exports to America. So the Australian economy
depends on the Chinese economy. Now, guys, let me
tell you where you can get these things. For
example, this image
is on a site called OIC
Word. OIC Word.
This site.  You search on Google, it will
bring up the site, then you go to the kettle section, it
says kettle of different countries, you
click on any country
you want and it will give you information about
exports and imports. I don't know, for example, you click
on China, here we click on the Australian dollar on the page, it will show you
what China exports to. Australia is a
great site, one part of it is money that didn't exist before.
Three or so years ago, when I was building
the site, I got great information
and really got to know the economy of the country.
You guys should study it, go and look around. You should
know the economies that you want to trade value in. You should
know what Australia imports and
what it exports because if the things it
imports become expensive, the Australian dollar
weakens. If the things it exports become expensive, the
Australian dollar strengthens because the demand for the
Australian dollar increases. So if we do
n't know them, we can't use them. If
I gave you a place like a year in the previous parts,
if we  We don't know that Ukraine is a
food exporter. We don't know what the impact of the war in
Ukraine is on the global economy. So go and look it up. It's
very interesting. It's
very enjoyable for me. Be sure to go and see this site
and see different countries.
Get to know the trading partners because trading partners
affect each other. For example, the United States is China's
largest trading partner. China is
America's largest trading partner. So the economies of China and the United States are in the
same direction. Again, there are
divergences. Divergence means there are
differences that cause
our market to fluctuate. But I want to
say that it is in the same direction. What does it mean by in the same direction?
If there is a recession in the United States, it will happen
in China too.
So go to the OEC website. Look it up. Look it up. It's
really interesting and useful. So
here we found out that Australia is a trading partner of
China. So the Australian economy is affected by the
Chinese economy. What are the things it exports?
Ivor or iron ore and coal or coal. These two
constitute the largest part of exports.
Gold here, look at gold. Gold exports 5.
Australia is one of the exporters of gold. It is
gold. It is gold. They
mine gold. Canada is the same. Canada is
in the previous slide. Now I didn't notice, but they
have high gold mining. This causes what
happens? Gold has a correlation with the Australian dollar.
Now, if
gold always grows, the Australian dollar grows.
No, this is not going to happen at all.
Everyone who comes to you will say, "Gold
has a correlation with gold. There is nothing like that."
The market was that simple, everyone was making a profit.
We don't have anything like that.
We don't have anything like that that's that simple. No, I
told you guys. Fundamentals are
made up of different parts. Different parts
mean several factors that you should
monitor together. For example, one day, this
impact of gold on the Australian dollar was
very small. 5 of its exports are now forming gold.
What
happened to 5 of its exports? It is gold and it is
not as influential as the Chinese economy, which affects the price of
iron ore, coal, and
other factors. Sentiment affects the Australian dollar.
Monetary policy transitions, central bank conditions,
no, it's not that simple.
Guys, there is nothing simple in this market.
Anyone who tells you that this market
is simple is
selling you a dream. So please don't believe these things too
quickly or get excited. Someone
says, "I didn't know that oil has a coalition code." I'll
tell you this,
but I have to tell you several other things.
Finally, I'll tell you how to
use these things. But just
knowing these little things doesn't mean that
trading is that easy. So
guys, another of Australia's exports
is petroleum gas. Australia is one of the largest
exporters of LNG. This is liquefied gas
that is transported by tankers. So
guys, here we have found that the Australian dollar
is correlated with the Chinese economy, and two
commodities that are very influential are iron ore and
coal. Then it goes to petroleum gas or
LNG. Then it goes to the three worlds. So let's go to the
next slide, which I'll show you in the picture.
This kind of
influence, we have the IDC here,
our blue chart next to the
price of iron ore and coal, iron ore becomes yellow,
coal becomes red,
you can see the correlation. Here, for example,
you see coal, here too, there is a complete
iron ore collision, it is clear how it is, the collision is completely
direct, that is, if the price of iron ore and coal
increases, the Australian dollar will also strengthen.
If the price of these decreases, the
Australian dollar will also weaken. So iron ore and
coal are two key commodities for the
Australian dollar. Let's move on to the next slide, where
I brought the correlation of the Chinese and Australian economies.
Here you see the index of 50
large Chinese companies, or
A7, A50, and the correlation with IDI.
The impact of the Chinese economy on the
Australian economy. Let's move on to the next economy, New Zealand.
What is the situation in New Zealand? New Zealand's largest
one of its
largest trading partners is China, and then
Australia, and then America. These are the three main points of the
story. China and Australia are more important.
In general, we say that the New Zealand economy
is dependent on the Chinese and Australian economies, that is, the news from
Australia and China comes.  Guys, if
negative news comes from China, it will make New Zealand
negative. If positive news comes from China, it will make the
New Zealand dollar positive. The impact
means that this positive news comes from China, that is, the
Chinese stock market indices or the China A50 will grow
and this correlation is with the
NZD, the NZD, and the
Australian dollar will also rise in the same way. So,
China's largest trading partners, Australia and the
United States, are
completely related to the New Zealand economy, and the New Zealand dollar is
correlated or affected by the price of dairy products in the world. But
guys, this correlation is not like the previous correlation,
that is, the correlation of Canada with oil and India with
coal and gold. It is not such a
high correlation. It is more that it is
affecting the New Zealand dollar and
other fundamental factors. As I told you,
fundamentals are not one thing. Here we have found out what
New Zealand's largest trading partners and largest exports are.
For example, here you can see that 16 of its exports
Milk, then I say meat,
meat and wool of sheep and in general,
they export animals. They export wood
and what do they say, they export wood and fruit and generally
food and most of New Zealand
is an exporter. I'm wrong. I mean, you see that I'm making a mistake somewhere.
Sorry, I'll
record a video. It's not like that. I'll pass it on. And
not this. Well, now here you have the correlation of NZD UC
and the Chinese economy. You can see how it is.
I compared the China A50 or the China stock market index with NZD UC,
which has a direct correlation. That is, if the Chinese economy
weakens, the New Zealand dollar weakens, the
Chinese economy grows, and the New Zealand dollar also
grows. Here you see the correlation of IDI and
NZD. Here we
have the D to J Furs NZD UI and IDI UC, which
actually have a high correlation and move together. They
are completely in line with each other. But this is
not the reason why they always move together. I'm
saying again that the IDI NZD pair itself is a
world and now I'm saying what things
are influential. So  Guys, the NZD and NZD are correlated with each other,
or we can say that the NZD and
NZD move together. They move together. The
next picture is the price of dairy products and the NZD
UC that you have on the monthly time frame. You can see
how it affects and
what changes in the price of the NZD caused the movement of the NZD.
Well, this is the New Zealand dollar. Now let's
go to these risky currencies in the
forex market, the stock market, and the commodity
market. We said why they are risky.
Now let's talk about safe assets, guys.
Why are these assets safe?
A bond is two dollars, a yen, and a franc. Why
are these safe? First of all, bonds,
guys. A safe investment with a fixed interest rate. The
bonds you buy are like this: you
pay money, you buy the debt of a place. For example, I'm
talking about US debt here, US government debt,
US Treasury debt. You pay money,
as an investor, you buy US debt.
They give you a paper, the
price of a bond is, for example, $1000. This paper
has a fixed interest rate, for example, it has a 3% interest rate. What does that
mean? At the end of year 3, it is worth
$100. For example, you will receive interest. It has a
fixed interest rate. Now, if the world situation gets bad, it will give you interest. If the situation gets good, it will give you interest. I want to say that in general, we recognize bonds as an asset because they have a fixed interest rate. And
now, I would like to add that in the
bond market, we also have a series of high-yield bonds
or risky bonds and
a series of safe or safe bonds. For example, the
US government's bonds are very safe because because the
US government is backed by the US Treasury, which
never gives or
defaults on its debt, or if it goes bankrupt and cannot
pay its debt, the default rate is less than 1.
So this asset is a risky asset. It
is a conditional asset. Now, consider this with
bonds. For example, a company that has been established for 3 years issues
bonds.  Bonds
mean debt comes to the investor and says, "Come on,
do my financing. I'll give you a profit.
I'll take your money. I'll
invest in my company. I'll make a profit. I'll give
you a percentage of the profit.
Bonds, for example, are for a 3-year-old company.
This has a higher risk than
US bonds. So in the bond market, we
have different risks. And absolutely, guys, the
bond market is very important. The bond market, you
could say, is the clearest, most transparent market
that gives different signals to
other markets and is very, very efficient.
In that section, the bond section, we
have another section about bonds. I'll explain it completely.
How do we use the bond market
in the market? But here I want to
tell you to get to know bonds. Because they
give a fixed interest and we know them as a
safe asset, they have low risk. I'll
tell you something else here. Guys,
suppose a company wants to
do financing. That is, raise money.
What can it do? It can come and become a stock.
Sell ​​it means you can split the shares, they call it in
Iran. Yes,
then offer its shares in the market, meaning you can
divide the company into different pieces,
divide them into small pieces, sell them to the
shareholders and they can issue bonds or debt. I
said debt, meaning that I will announce,
sir, I want to auction bonds, I will
auction bonds. You come and buy my
bonds or debt, and I will give you a
fixed interest. Now, here is the point of the difference between bonds and stocks.
We said it is a way of financing.
What is the difference between bonds and stocks? Suppose the
company goes bankrupt and the government comes and sells the
company's assets, and then what does it do with the
money it gets? First, it
goes and gives the debt to those who
bought the company's debt bonds. That is, first,
the government decides with those who
have the bonds of this company, not the shares of the
shareholders. The shareholders share in the
company's losses and profits. That is why
now, the
company is right.  It has the potential to make a lot of profit.
The shareholder is likely to make a profit here,
but there is also the possibility of bankruptcy.
On the other hand, it also has a higher risk. So
bondholders have priority over
stockholders. And that's how it is. The difference between bonds
and stocks is that the second is the US dollar. Why
is it safe? Because it is
backed by the largest economy in the world, an
economy that accounts for 25% of the global economy, or a
quarter of the global economy. We know the
US economy as the largest
economy. Because it is backed by the largest
economy, it is safe. They
trust it very much. It is the global reserve currency.
Central banks buy it to prevent fluctuations
and things like exports and imports, a shortage of
dollar liquidity.
And another reason why it is safe is that it is the
global reserve currency. The third reason is that it is
used in global trade and the valuation of
financial assets based on the dollar.
For example, the US stock market has half the value of the world. If you
leave aside all the stock markets, the
US half of the story means that half of the value of the global stock market is the
US. And this market is priced in dollars.
And when the stock market
decreases, the demand for dollars increases.
And another reason why the dollar is safe
is the Japanese yen. Why is it safe? Because it
has a positive trade balance and payment. What does that mean?
Japan has been negative for a few years now,
but over
time, on average, it has been an exporting country
rather than an importing country. It is a
very active manufacturing country. It has a high-tech country.
Many people
work around the clock. It has a high economic ranking. It is a
great country that
has a positive trade balance. That is, it exports more than it
imports. And this causes
Japanese assets abroad to be high.
And the increase in assets abroad causes
assets to return to Japan in times of crisis. For
example, there is a crisis in the United States
or in the world or Japan itself.
This causes the Japanese to
ask for money from foreigners to support their economy.
Sir, give me my money. This causes the demand for the
yen from the world to increase in order to
pay for the Japanese's bad deeds. And this causes the
growth of the Japanese yen in risk-off conditions or in
times of  If a crisis occurs, low interest rates
are another reason. We have a topic on
interest rate differentials. Now, I
will explain it in detail in the central bank section. Interest rate differentials
are one of the factors that cause a
currency to fluctuate. Any bank that has a
perspective that can
lower interest rates will weaken the currency and
capital will be withdrawn from it. But
Japan, because it has such a low interest rate,
has a negative interest rate of one tenth. The market
does not expect it to lower its interest rate because it is
practically impossible and there is no benefit.
Therefore, the Japanese yen does not weaken
and in the risk-off sentiment, capital will move towards it.
Another type of carry trade is called a carry trade. I do
n't know if I'm
pronouncing it correctly in Persian. What is a carry trade? We're talking
about interest rates. We're talking about interest rates. We're talking about an
investor borrowing from an economy with a lower interest rate
and
investing in an economy with a higher interest rate. The
interest rate here is, for example, 5 here,
1 here. The investor makes a profit on this difference.
When risk-off occurs, the demand for the yen increases. The demand
for Japan increases because
investors have to
pay debts to Japanese banks and Japanese institutions.
Why is the Swiss franc a safe haven? Why is it a
low-risk asset? Because it
has a positive trade balance and payment. Like above, the
stability of the financial and monetary system of Swiss banks is
famous. The central bank itself
has a different system altogether. It has a
number of different features
that I don't think I can explain in this series
because there are many more cases that we ca
n't fix, but I made a video about it.
Follow the channel and you can
access that video to see why the
Swiss central bank is different from the others.  What are banks? The
interest rates of children are low. It has a low interest rate.
Like Japan and the government
has very low debt. The government has very low debt.
One of the things that makes different currencies have
different risks is the debt discussion. You've heard that the
debt of this government is in the GD before,
for example in the US it's over 100 and in
Japan it's 250. But the debt is mostly domestic, so it's
not a negative factor. In Switzerland, this
issue is very low, meaning the government's debt
is extremely low. And in my last slide, you can see
that when the risk-off happens, I
explained their rates separately to you and I
showed a chart of what it is and how it affects you.
Now, when the risk-off happens,
what
happens is the growth of safe assets. The yen,
dollar and franc bonds grow. Here you
guys are seeing March 20020.
What happened in March 2020? February and March 2020. Corona came.
Corona came. People were afraid. They didn't spend. The economy
went into recession. The economy became extremely weak.
You can see what happened here. Eddie, Eddie, Eddie,
Eddie, all Eddie vs. vs.
safe currencies.  ADINAC, all of these things are
decreasing, what does it mean? CHF,
yen and dollar are growing against the AUD, it
weakened. I said, supply, what happens to capital when risk-off is happening?
Capital is moving out of AUD, it is moving towards the
yen, it is moving towards the franc, it is moving towards the
dollar, it is moving towards bonds. You see all
four of these things decreasing, which
means that the yen, the US dollar and the franc are strengthening, and you see the
yield on the 10-year US bonds.
Guys, when the
Shub chart is down, it means that the price of bonds has gone up.
I explain this in the full bond videos.
And here you can see how
these assets are correlated. You can see that
they are completely correlated with each other, which means that
they all strengthened together. Then, you
can almost say that they all weakened together. Now, of
course, I have to say that this is where there is so much correlation.
Why is it because during the
Corona period, there is fear only in the
market, fear only in the economy, and fear means
risk-off, which means sentiment is very influential.  90
Sentiment 10 Funds Now it's technical,
now it's not technical, it's not really here anymore,
sentiment is the first thing, no matter how many
levels you draw or I don't know, say support here,
this doesn't work, because the market is
scared and when it's scared, it does its job.
We are seeing that sentiment effect in the market. I hope it was
useful for you. We
definitely have work to do with sentiment in the next videos in the
things we want to examine. And in
this part, I completely opened the sentiment map for you.
Again, I emphasize once again,
guys, stay in touch with us. Is there a question, a
suggestion, is there something you didn't understand? Do you
have questions
about the fundamentals, how the market
moved like this, how it happened here,
everything in the market?
Follow our Telegram and Instagram channels and
ask your questions there. Your questions
will help me
prepare parts for you at the end of this series and
provide explanations that will clarify your questions and
ambiguities.
If you have any questions, please tell me so
that I can find out where the problem is and explain it to you
more. Let me know. The fundamentals are
very easy, guys. Even the
fundamentals are not like that. It
may be a bit difficult at first, but the
topics can really be simplified like this. Guys,
I really wish there was a course like this
4 or 5 years ago. I would have been
much further ahead. These are all the things I
am telling you now, and I simplified them.
For example, you have to go and get them piece by piece
from different places and different external sources,
and it takes a lot of time for you. But this
complete set comes and tells you everything. In
my opinion, it has become much easier. There is a lot of information.
Other colleagues have taken the trouble to
explain the topics. I also wanted to
prepare a complete set for traders who will continue to get
acquainted with the Forex market, the
financial markets, the bond market,
Forex, and others.  I will get to know them so that I can share my experiences with
them. Thank God, in these two or
three years, we have been able to guide many people and
help them find their way in this
market. Now I am at your service
and I am very happy to record this collection.
If you like this collection, be sure to
leave me a positive comment below the
Frachart collection
so that I can get energy too.